Guide to the James Beard Papers ca. 1950-1980 MSS.263
Fales Library and Special Collections
James Beard Papers
ca. 1950-1980
Fales Library and Special Collections
Beard, James, 1903-1985
MSS.263
32 Linear Feet
Related Materials
James Beard Collection
The Cecily Brownstone Papers
The Les Dames d'Escoffier New York Archive
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into thirteen series:
Although the collection was partially processed when it arrived at Fales, there was little original order, and no order that could be definitively credited to James Beard. Therefore, some rearrangement was undertaken.
The collection is grouped into twelve series based on type of material. Each series is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically based on the information provided. All original folder titles and arrangements have been maintained. Descriptions are at the folder level.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials relating to James Beard's professional career as a chef, food writer and cooking instructor, as well as some materials relating to his personal life. Materials include drafts of manuscripts and articles, galley proofs, scripts for television shows, correspondence, date books, itinerary, recipes, cooking lessons, photographs, printed material, clippings and media.
The collection is arranged into 12 series:
Series I: Manuscripts
Series II:Assorted Writing
Series III:Recurring Television Shows and Columns
Series IV: Correspondence
Series V:Personal
Series VI: Recipes
Series VII:Events
Series VIII: Printed Material
Series IX:Clippings
Series X:Miscellaneous
Series XI: Photographs
Series XII: Media
Biographical Note
James Andrews Beard, world-renowned chef, was born in Portland, Oregon on May 5, 1903. He studied briefly at Reed College in Portland but left in 1923 to join a touring theatrical troupe and pursue a career as an actor and singer. In the mid-1930s he began to supplement his income with catering work, and in 1937 he settled in New York and opened a gourmet food shop, Hors D'Oeuvre, Inc. The work at the shop led to Beard's first book, Hors d'Oeuvres and Canapés, in 1940.
During the war years, Beard served with the U.S. Seamen's Service, establishing sailors' canteens in Rio de Janeiro, Puerto Rico, Panama and Marseille. When he returned to New York he resumed writing cookbooks, publishing prolifically and establishing himself as America's most noted culinary authority. In 1946 he was given his own segment on a pioneering television program, NBC's "I Love to Eat," becoming one of the first TV chefs.
Over the years, Beard contributed articles and columns to numerous magazines, including Gourmet, House and Garden and Woman's Day. In the 1970s he wrote a syndicated newspaper column, "Beard on Food."
In 1955 Beard established the James Beard Cooking School in New York, and for many years he served as a consultant to food producers and restaurateurs.
Beard published over twenty books in his lifetime, among them The Fireside Cookbook, The James Beard Cookbook, Delights and Prejudices, a Memoir with Recipes, and James Beard's Theory and Practice of Good Cooking.
James Beard died on January 21, 1985 at age 81.
Provenance
The collection was donated to NYU Libraries in 2008 by The American Heritage Center at the University of Wyoming.
Food industry and trade; Television scripts; Cooking schools.; Food writing.; Menus.; Datebooks.; Photographs.; Personal papers.; Notes.; Recipes.; Cookery, American.; Culinary industry.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Cookbooks.; Woman's day; Gourmet; Child, Julia; Beard, James, 1903-1985; Wilson, José; Jones, Judith, 1924-
- Series I: Manuscripts, 1980-1981; 167592
  Scope and Content
  This series contains manuscripts for many of Beard's numerous cookbooks. It is arrange into fifteen subseries based on project. The folders within each subseries are arranged alphabetically and then chronoligcally, if dated. The "Unidentified" subseries contains discrete records that appear to have been part of larger, unidentified projects. Criteria for this subseries included pagination and titles that suggest the draft process of writing.
  - Subseries A: Beard on Bread, undated; 172891
    - Galley Page Proof [pages 145-176 missing], 1973; 172892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Uncorrected Proof, 1973; 201122 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - [Draft, annotated] (1 of 2), undated; 172893 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - [Draft, annotated] (2 of 2), undated; 201119 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - [Draft, annotated] (1 of 2), undated; 201120 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - [Draft, annotated] (2 of 2), undated; 201121 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Introductions and Notes, undated; 172894 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Beard on Food, 200295
    - [Typescript, annotated] (1 of 3), 1974; 201123 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - [Typescript, annotated] (2 of 3), 1974; 201124 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - [Typescript, annotated] (3 of 3), 1974; 201125 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Uncorrected Proof, 1974; 201126 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Fowl and Game Bird Cookery, 1979; 167712
    - [Typescript, annotated] (1 of 2), 1979; 201127 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Typescript, annotated] (2 of 2), 1979; 201128 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Index [annotated], undated; 201129 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: Gospel, 200297
    - The Gospel According to St. James, 1974; 201130 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Gospel: Sauteing, 1975; 201131 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gospel, undated; 201132 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gospel, undated; 201133 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Gospel, undated; 201134 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Gospel: American Way, undated; 201135 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Gospel: Baking, undated; 201136 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Gospel: Frying, undated; 201137 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Gospel: [Frying], undated; 201138 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Gospel: Grilling and Broiling, undated; 201139 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Gospel: Ne[...] to Hands, undated; 201141 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Gospel [recipes, handwritten], undated; 201140 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Gospel: Roasting, undated; 201142 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Gospel: Stock, undated; 201143 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Subseries E: The Great Cooks Cookbook, 1974; 184415
    - [Drafts], 1974; 181482 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Preliminarily Edited Draft (1 of 2), 1974; 184416 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Preliminarily Edited Draft (2 of 2), 1974; 184417 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Subseries F: How to Cook, 180047
    - Things Needed for How To Cook, Jan. 20, 1976; 201144 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - How To Cook, undated; 180036 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - How To Cook [Draft, annotated] (1 of 4), undated; 180037 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - How To Cook [Draft, annotated] (2 of 4), undated; 201145 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - How To Cook [Draft, annotated] (3 of 4), undated; 201146 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - How To Cook [Draft, annotated] (4 of 4), undated; 201147 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - How To Cook: Baking, undated; 201148 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - How To Cook: Boiling, undated; 201149 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - How To Cook: Braising, undated; 180038 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - How To Cook: Broiling and Grilling, undated; 180039 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - How To Cook: Chilling and Freezing, undated; 201150 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - [How To Cook, Copies of Sketches], undated; 180051 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - How To Cook: Equipment Chapter, undated; 201151 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - How To Cook: First Edition and Revision, JW, undated; 201152 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - How To Cook: Frying, undated; 201153 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - How To Cook: Non-Cooking, undated; 201156 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - How To Cook: Roasting, undated; 201158 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - How To Cook: Sauteing, undated; 201157 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - [How To Cook], Sketches by Chapter, undated; 201159 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - How To Cook: Thickeners and Liasons, undated; 201160 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - [How To Cook] Working Outline, undated; 201161 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - List of Possible Sketches for How To Cook, undated; 201155 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Subseries G: Italian Notes, undated; 179617
    - Desserts (Definitions), undated; 179619 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Fish (Definitions), undated; 179620 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - French Cheese (Definitions), undated; 179618 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Hors d'Oeuvres (Definitions), undated; 201163 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Italian Notes [draft], undated; 201164 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - [Italian Notes, draft], undated; 201165 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Meat (Definitions), undated; 201166 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Not Categorized (Gone Over by JAB), undated; 201167 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Not Categorized (Not Gone Over by JAB), undated; 201168 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Restaurant Notes [annotated], undated; 201169 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Restaurant Notes [annotated], undated; 201170 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Sauce (Definitions), undated; 201171 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Soup (Definitions), undated; 201172 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Specialty (Definitions), undated; 201173 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Vegetable (Definitions), undated; 201174 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Wine (Definitions), undated; 201175 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Subseries H: James Beard's American Cookery, undated; 167709
    - Beef [annotated], undated; 201256 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Cheese [annotated], undated; 201257 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - [Draft, annotated], Intro (1 of 32), undated; 172602 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - [Draft, annotated], Appetizers (2 of 32), undated; 172600 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - [Draft, annotated], Salads (3 of 32), undated; 172603 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - [Draft, annotated], Soups (4 of 32), undated; 179615 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - [Draft, annotated], Eggs (5 of 32), undated; 173706 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - [Draft, annotated], Cheese (6 of 32), undated; 201176 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - [Draft, annotated], Fish and Shellfish (7 of 32), undated; 201177 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - [Draft, annotated], Poultry (8 of 32), undated; 201178 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - [Draft, annotated], Game (9 of 32), undated; 201179 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - [Draft, annotated], Beef 1 of 2 (10 of 32), updated; 201180 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - [Draft, annotated], Beef 2 of 2 (11 of 32), undated; 201181 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - [Draft, annotated], Veal (12 of 32), undated; 201182 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - [Draft, annotated], Lamb (13 of 32), undated; 201183 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - [Draft, annotated], Pork (14 of 32), undated; 201213 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - [Draft, annotated], Ham and Bacon (15 of 32), undated; 201214 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - [Draft, annotated], Sauces for Meats, Fish and Vegetables (16 of 32), undated; 201215 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - [Draft, annotated], Vegetables 1 of 2 (17 of 32), undated; 201240 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - [Draft, annotated], Vegetables 2 of 2 (18 of 32), undated; 201241 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - [Draft, annotated], Potatoes (19 of 32), undated; 201242 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - [Draft, annotated], Grains and Pastes (20 of 32), undated; 201243 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - [Draft, annotated], Dried Beans, Peas and Lentils (21 of 32), undated; 201244 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - [Draft, annotated], Pies and Pastry (22 of 32), undated; 201245 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - [Draft, annotated], Cakes (23 of 32), undated; 201246 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - [Draft, annotated], Cookies (24 of 32), undated; 201247 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - [Draft, annotated], Puddings, Ice Creams and Dessert Sauces (25 of 32), undated; 201248 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - [Draft, annotated], Fruit (26 of 32), undated; 201249 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - [Draft, annotated], Bread (27 of 32), undated; 201250 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - [Draft, annotated], Sandwiches (28 of 32), undated; 201251 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - [Draft, annotated], Pickles and Preserves (29 of 32), undated; 201252 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - [Draft, annotated], Candy (30 of 32), undated; 201253 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - [Draft, annotated], Miscellaneous [...] to Transfer... (31 of 32), undated; 201254 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - [Draft, annotated] (32 of 32), undated; 201255 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Dried Beans, Peas and Lentils [annotated], undated; 201390 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Eggs [annotated], undated; 201391 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Fish and Shellfish [annotated], undated; 201392 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Game [annotated], undated; 201393 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Grains and Pastes [annotated], undated; 201394 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Ham and Bacon [annotated], undated; 201395 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Lamb [annotated], undated; 201396 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Pork [annotated], undated; 201397 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Potatoes [annotated], undated; 201398 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Poultry [annotated], undated; 201399 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Sauces [annotated], undated; 201400 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Veal [annotated], undated; 201401 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Vegetables [annotated] (1 of 2), undated; 201402 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Vegetables [annotated] (2 of 2), undated; 201403 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Subseries I: James Beard's American Table, 201404
    - Suggestions for James Beard's American Table Cookbook, undated; 173707 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Subseries J: James Beard's Basic Guide to Good Cooking, 201405
    - [copy of title page], undated; 201406 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Re: Concordance for James Beard's Basic Guide to Good Cooking, undated; 201407 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Subseries K: The New Fish Cookery, 184421
    - Fish Book Revision, 1974; 184422 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - [Draft, annotated] (1of 4), 1976; 167710 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - [Draft, annotated] (2 of 4), 1976; 201408 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - [Draft, annotated] (3 of 4), 1976; 201409 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - [Draft, annotated] (4 of 4), 1976; 201410 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Index [annotated], undated; 201411 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Subseries L: The New James Beard, 167708
    - [Draft, annotated] (1 of 5), 1980; 201412 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - [Draft, annotated] (2 of 5), 1980; 201413 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - [Draft, annotated] (3 of 5), 1980; 201414 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - [Draft, annotated] (4 of 5), 1980; 201415 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - [Draft, annotated] (5 of 5), 1980; 201416 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - [Draft, annotated] (1 of 3), 1981; 201417 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - [Draft, annotated] (2 of 3), 1981; 201418 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - [Draft, annotated] (3 of 3), 1981; 201419 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - [Front pages, annotated], undated; 201422 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Index [annotated], undated; 201423 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Recipe Listing (pp 1-30), undated; 201424 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Running Heads [annotated], undated; 201425 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Page Proofs (1 of 7), 1981; 211975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Page Proofs (2 of 7), 1981; 211976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Page Proofs (3 of 7), 1981; 211977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Page Proofs (4 of 7), 1981; 211978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Page Proofs (5 of 7), 1981; 211979 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Page Proofs (6 of 7), 1981; 211980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Page Proofs (7 of 7), 1981; 211981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Subseries M: 1000 Recipes, 201420
    - Beard, 1000 Recipes, undated; 201421 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries N: Theory and Practice of Good Cooking, 1976; 167949
    - Manuscript: Theory and Practice, 1974; 181368 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - [Draft, annotated] (1 of 13), August 1979; 180893 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - [Draft, annotated], (2 of 13), August 1979; 180894 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - [Draft, annotated], front matter and "equipment" (3 of 13), August 1979; 180895 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - [Draft, annotated], Boiling (4 of 13), August 1979; 180896 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - [Draft, annotated], Roasting, (5 of 13), August 1979; 180897 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - [Draft, annotated], Broiling and Grilling, (6 of 13), August 1979; 180898 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - [Draft, annotated], Braising, (7 of 13), August 1979; 180899 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - [Draft, annotated], Sauteing (8 of 13), August 1979; 180900 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - [Draft, annotated], Frying (9 of 13), August 1979; 180901 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - [Draft, annotated], Baking (10 of 13), August 1979; 180902 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - [Draft, annotated], Thickeners and Liasons (11 of 13), August 1979; 180907 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - [Draft, annotated], Non-Cooking (12 of 13), August 1979; 180908 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - [Draft, annotated], Chilling and Freezing (13 of 13), August 1979; 180910 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Subseries O: Unidentified Manuscripts, 179605
    - Appetizers, undated; 201426 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Appetizers, undated; 201427 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Appetizers, undated; 201428 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Appetizers, undated; 201429 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Appetizers (copies for J.B.), undated; 179647 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Appetizers, typed, finished, undated; 201430 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Beans, undated; 201431 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Beans, undated; 201432 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Beard, meat chapter, undated; 201433 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Beef, undated; 201434 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Beef, undated; 201435 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Beef, undated; 201436 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Beef, undated; 201437 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Beef: Introduction, undated; 179606 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Beef Originals, undated; 205177 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - [Beef recipes, paginated], undated; 201438 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Book Notes, undated; 201439 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Braising, undated; 182207 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Bread, undated; 182203 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - [Bread], undated; 201440 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - [Bread], undated; 201441 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Breads and Cookies, Judith's Copy, undated; 201442 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Breads, Griddle Cakes and Waffles [annotated], undated; 201443 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cakes, undated; 201444 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Cakes, undated; 201445 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cakes, undated; 201446 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cakes, undated; 201447 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Cakes and Cookies - edited copies given to Robert Carmack 3/25/79, 1979; 185119 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cakes and Desserts, undated; 179659 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Candy, undated; 201448 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Candy, undated; 201449 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Candy, undated; 201450 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Cheese: Introduction, undated; 201451 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Cheese and Eggs, undated; 179607 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Concordance - all typed to date, plus..., undated; 179655 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Concordance, continuation on "Flour", [1976]; 179645 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Concordance, copies to J.W., J.J. and J.B. 7/20, July 20, 1976; 179644 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Concordance, copies sent to J.W. and J.J. 7/28, July 28, [1976]; 179643 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - [Concordance drafts], undated; 201548 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Cookies, undated; 180464 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cookies, undated; 201550 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Cookies, undated; 201551 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - [Cookies], undated; 202322 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Cooking Terms, undated; 201549 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - [Copies of Illustrations], undated; 201552 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - [Copies of Illustrations], undated; 201553 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Desserts, undated; 185123 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Desserts: Introduction, undated; 179608 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Desserts (J.B.), undated; 202323 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Desserts, Judith Jones, undated; 201554 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Desserts (Originals), undated; 202324 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Dupe Beard Samples, undated; 201555 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Eggs, undated; 201556 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Eggs and Cheese, revised, undated; 179663 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Fish, undated; 201581 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - [Fish], undated; 201582 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Fish (Copies for J.B.), undated; 202325 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Fish and Shellfish, undated; 201583 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - [Fish and Shellfish], undated; 201584 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - For Meat/Poultry and Game Chapters, undated; 201585 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Fruit, undated; 201586 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - [Fruit], undated; 202331 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Game, undated; 201587 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Game, undated; 201588 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Grains: Rice, undated; 201589 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Grains: Rice, undated; 201590 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Hors d'Oeuvre, undated; 182176 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Hors d'Oeuvres, 117 recipes, undated; 179646 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Index, undated; 180088 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Introduction, undated; 201591 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Introduction, undated; 201593 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Introduction, undated; 201592 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Introduction to the Book, undated; 179613 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Introduction to the Book, undated; 201594 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - [Introductions by Beard], undated; 201595 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Italian Sausage and Related Products, undated; 201596 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Jose's Comments, undated; 179661 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Judith Jones; Pasta, Rice, Grain, Dried Beans; Master Copy, undated; 201597 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Judith Jones, "Salads", undated; 201598 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Judith Jones, "Soups" 73, "Fish and Shellfish" 106, undated; 201599 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - [Knopf Envelope], October 23, 1974; 184654 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Lamb, undated; 201600 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Lamb, undated; 201601 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Lamb, undated; 179610 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Lamb, undated; 201602 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Main Courses, undated; 201603 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Meat and Poultry, undated; 201604 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Meat, Fowl and Fish Pies, undated; 201610 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Meat, Poultry and Game, typed, undated; 201605 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Meats, undated; 201606 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - [Miscellaneous], undated; 182180 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - [Notes and Head Notes], undated; 201607 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Originals, Eggs and Cheese, undated; 201608 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Originals, fish and shellfish - already done and to be done, undated; 179654 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Originals, Vegetables, undated; 184674 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Outline for Book, undated; 201609 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Pasta, Rice and Grain, undated; 179662 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Pasta, Rice and Grain, undated; 201611 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - [Pastry], undated; 202326 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - [Pastries], undated; 182202 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Pickles and Preserves, undated; 201612 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Pickles and Preserves, undated; 201613 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Pickles and Preserves, undated; 201614 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Pies, undated; 201615 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Pies, undated; 201616 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Pies and Pastries, undated; 201617 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Pork, undated; 201618 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Pork, undated; 201619 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Pork, undated; 201620 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Pork, undated; 201621 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Potatoes, undated; 201622 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - [Potatoes], undated; 201623 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Poultry, undated; 179611 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - [Poultry], undated; 201624 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Poultry: Chicken, undated; 201625 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Preliminary Chapter List and Notes, undated; 201626 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - [Pudding, Frosting, Ice Cream], undated; 201627 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Salads, undated; 179789 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Salads, undated; 182215 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Salads, undated; 201628 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Salads, undated; 201629 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Salads, undated; 201630 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Salads (Originals), undated; 202327 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Sandwiches, undated; 201631 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Sandwiches, undated; 201632 (Box 7, Folder 34)